Finding Aid for Michigan Citizen Records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Citizen Records
1933-2015
1990-2010
Michigan Citizen (Highland Park, Mich.)
189.2 MB online
5 microfilms
30 linear feet in 57 boxes; including oversize
2009137 Bj 2
The Michigan Citizen was a weekly African American newspaper published from 1978 to 2014, and distributed in Benton Harbor, the City of Highland Park, and the City of Detroit, Michigan. The Michigan Citizen Records consist of the weekly issues of the Michigan Citizen newspaper, the subject files used by the newspaper staff, reporter's notes, correspondence written to the editor of the Michigan Citizen, and hundreds of photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Michigan Citizen (donor no. 11240 ) in multiple accessions in 2015.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The Michigan Citizen newspaper, originally called the Citizen, was founded in Benton Harbor, Michigan in 1978 by Charles and Teresa Maxwell-Kelly. It was a weekly publication, distributed on Sundays from November 1978 until December 2014. Since its beginning, the paper maintained a strong pro-community, progressive editorial stance, and was directed toward Michigan's African American and progressive-minded community. The Kelly's experiences as community organizers provided the newspaper's editorial focus. Founded on the belief that people made good decisions if armed with good information, the paper attempted to provide voice to the views of ordinary citizens in a city where African Americans were the majority. From its beginning, the paper was often considered by some to be controversial, insisting on holding elected officials accountable for their actions and providing sole coverage of grassroots groups and movements.
The Michigan Citizen began as a 12-page tabloid with an original circulation of 3,000 papers distributed in the Benton Harbor area. It eventually became a 16-page broadsheet newspaper with a statewide circulation of 56,000 copies. The Citizen expanded in 1980 when a group of ministers in Muskegon asked the paper to serve their residents. An office was opened in Muskegon Heights, but closed two years later. A distributor continued to circulate the paper there until 2008. The Citizen opened a Detroit-area office in the City of Highland Park in 1985 in order to serve Metro-Detroit while maintaining the Benton Harbor office. Although in its seventh year of continuous weekly publication at that point, the Citizen became the Michigan Citizen in 1985 in order to settle a costly lawsuit filed by the Hamtramck Citizen.
The Michigan Citizen became the official publication of the City of Highland Park and was the successful bidder for years publishing the Wayne County tax foreclosure list. The paper was also distributed at over 2 dozen locations in Detroit, including shops, bookstores, and restaurants. Catherine Kelly became the publisher of the Michigan Citizen upon the death of her father, Charles Kelly, in 2006. The Michigan Citizen published its last weekly edition on December 28, 2014, and thereafter ceased publication.
The collection is arranged into five series: Newspaper Issues, Subject Files, Reporter's Notes, Correspondence, and Photographs.
The Michigan Citizen Records document various points of political, social, and economic history and events, relating to African Americans, that took place in southern Michigan from 1978-2015, with specific focuses on the cities of Benton Harbor, Detroit, and Highland Park.
Subjects:
African American authors--United States--20th century.; African American civil rights workers--Michigan.; African American motion picture actors and actresses--United States--20th century.; African American musicians--United States--20th century.; African American neighborhoods--Michigan.; African American newspapers--Michigan.; African American political activists--Michigan.; African American prisoners--Michigan.; African Americans--Michigan--Newspapers.; African Americans--Michigan--Social conditions--20th century.; African Americans--Michigan--Social conditions--21st century.; Benton Harbor (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Highland Park (Mich.); Michigan Citizen (Highland Park, Mich.); Newspapers--Michigan.; Wayne County (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Events--Michigan.; Public speaking--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; Digital file formats.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Newspaper Issues, 1978-2015
  The Newspaper Issues series (12 linear feet and 5 microfilm reels, 1978-2014) includes the weekly issues of the Michigan Citizen newspaper from 1978 to 2014, with a few exceptions.
  - 1978-1994, 5 microfilms
    (currently out for digitization)
  - 1980 (Box 1)
    (missing most issues)
  - 1981 (Box 2)
  - 1982 (Box 3)
    (missing all issues up to August 4)
  - 1983 (Box 4)
    (missing issues for May 4 and May 25)
  - 1984 (Box 5)
  - 1985 (Box 6)
  - 1986 (Box 7)
    (with gaps)
  - 1987 (Box 8)
    (missing January 4 issue)
  - 1988 (Box 9)
  - 1989 (Box 10)
  - 1990 (Box 11)
    (missing issues after November 24)
  - 1991, 1994 (Box 12)
    (1991 has gaps; 1994 missing December issues)
  - 1995 (Box 13)
    (missing February 12 issue)
  - 1996 (Box 14)
    (missing July 7 issue)
  - 1997 (Box 15)
    (missing issues for January 19 and December 7)
  - 1998 (Box 16)
    (missing September 20 issue)
  - 1999 (Box 17)
  - 2000 (Box 18)
  - 2001 (Box 19)
    (missing September 2 issue)
  - 2002 (Box 20)
    (missing issues for April 14 and May 19)
  - 2003 (Box 21)
    (missing issues for April 6 and November 30)
  - 2004 (Box 22)
  - 2005 (Box 23)
  - 2006 (Box 24)
  - 2007 (Box 25)
    (missing November 25 issue)
  - 2008 (Box 26)
    (missing May 25 issue)
  - 2009 (Box 27)
  - 2010 (Box 28)
  - 2011 (Box 29)
  - 2012 (Box 30)
  - 2013 (Box 31)
  - 2014 (Box 32)
- Subject Files, 1960s-2000s
  The Subject Files series (6 linear feet, 1960s-2000s and undated) documents various topics of interest involving African Americans at both the national and local levels. Materials in this series are arranged alphabetically and served as additional resources for journalists when the paper was active.
  - Name Cards Index, A-Z (Box 33)
  - Access Scholarship Recipients, undated (Box 34)
  - Africa, 1990s (Box 34)
  - African American Association, undated (Box 34)
  - African American Women on Tour, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Aisha Shule-W.E.B. DuBois Preparatory Academy, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Jamil Allah, undated (Box 34)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc., 1990s (Box 34)
  - Alvin Ailey Dancers, undated (Box 34)
  - Apple Book Center, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Art, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Assessments-downtown, 1997 (Box 34)
  - Auto Hall of Fame, 1996 (Box 34)
  - B, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Baseball, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Basketball, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Beech Grove Investment Company and William J. Pulte, Inc. vs. Civil Rights Commission of the State of Michigan, 1960s (Box 34)
  - Benton Harbor, 1990s (Box 34)
  - Benton Harbor Airport, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Benton Harbor Lease/Purchase 285 Territorial Cornerstone, 1996-1998 (Box 34)
  - Benton Harbor Planning Territorial Road, 1996-1998 (Box 34)
  - Benton Harbor Prisoners, 1980s (Box 34)
  - Bethune-DuBois Fund, undated (Box 34)
  - Beverly Brewer/City Manager, 1990s (Box 34)
  - Black Artists, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Black Associates in State Employment, 1997 (Box 34)
  - Black Authors, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Black Business, 1995-2004 (Box 34)
  - Black Church Burnings, 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - Black College Football, undated (Box 34)
  - Black Community Crusade for Children (BCCC), 1996 (Box 34)
  - Black Democrats, 1996 (Box 34)
  - Blacks in Education, 2000s (Box 34)
  - Black Farmers, 1997 (Box 34)
  - Blacks in Government, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Black Historians, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Black History, scattered dates (Box 34)
  - Black History, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black Church History, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black History -- Detroit, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black History -- Letters, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black History -- Stories, 2006 (Box 35)
  - Black Inventors, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black Issues, 1987-1993 (Box 35)
  - Black Mayors, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black Panthers, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black Patriots Foundation, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Black Poets, undated (Box 35)
  - Black Talk Radio, undated (Box 35)
  - Black United Fund of Michigan, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Black Women, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Black World Books, undated (Box 35)
  - The Blockson Afro-American Collection, 1990 (Box 35)
  - Booker T. Washington Business Association, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Boxing, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Breast Cancer, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Breithaupt Career and Tech Center, undated (Box 35)
  - Bridal Fashions, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Bronner Brothers, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Brown Bag, undated (Box 35)
  - Buffalo Soldiers, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Canflow, 2001 (Box 35)
  - Candidates, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Maurice Carter, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Casino, 1996-1997 (Box 35)
  - Central Michigan University, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Central Optimist Club, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Charles Kelly Foundation, undated (Box 35)
  - Chess Records, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Chi Eta Phi Sorority, Inc., undated (Box 35)
  - C.I.A., 1996 (Box 35)
  - City Cab, undated (Box 35)
  - City of Detroit, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Civil Rights Movement, 1960s-1970s (Box 35)
  - Civil War Memorial, 1990s (Box 35)
  - Clergy, 1990s (Box 35)
  - Columnist, 1990s (Box 35)
  - Comedians, undated (Box 35)
  - Commissioner David Walker -- Special Planning Economic Development/Public Safety Committee Meeting, 1998 (Box 35)
  - Community Development Projects, Commercial Renovation Projects, 1998 (Box 35)
  - Congressional Black Caucus, scattered dates (Box 35)
  - Cornerstone Alliance, 1990s (Box 35)
  - Council of Elders, undated (Box 35)
  - Davison Freeway, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Downtown Development Authority, 1996-2000 (Box 35)
  - DECA, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Delta Sigma Theta, undated (Box 35)
  - The Democrat, 1996 (Box 35)
  - Denounce the 40 oz., 1997 (Box 35)
  - Detroit Community Health Connection, Inc., undated (Box 35)
  - Detroit Elected School Board, undated (Box 35)
  - Detroit Federation of Teachers, undated (Box 35)
  - Detroit Fire Department, undated (Box 35)
  - Detroit Historic Sites, 2000 (Box 35)
  - Detroit Institute of Art, 1990s (Box 36)
  - Detroit Police Officers Association, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Detroit Public Library, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - Detroit Public Schools, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - Detroit Tigers, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Detroit Urban League, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - DEVCO -- Sears/Bartlett Property, 2000 (Box 36)
  - Diane Bukowski and the Michigan Citizen vs. City of Detroit, 2002 (Box 36)
  - Downtown Detroit, undated (Box 36)
  - Ebonics, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Education, undated (Box 36)
  - Empowerment Zone, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Essence Magazine, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Eta Phi Beta Sorority, Inc., undated (Box 36)
  - Ethnic Newswatch, undated (Box 36)
  - Fannie Lou Hamer Political Action Committee, undated (Box 36)
  - Farmer Jack, undated (Box 36)
  - Fashion/Style, undated (Box 36)
  - Federation of the Independent Black Agenda, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Fihankra Internation (Michigan Chapter), 1996 (Box 36)
  - Fisher Theatre, undated (Box 36)
  - Flats Minutes, 1999-2004 (Box 36)
  - Focus Hope, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Food, undated (Box 36)
  - Football (NFL), undated (Box 36)
  - General Motors, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Glory Foods, 1997 (Box 36)
  - Golf, undated (Box 36)
  - Gospel Music Hall of Fame, 1996 (Box 36)
  - The Great Migration, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - H -- Entertainers, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - Haiti, undated (Box 36)
  - Harlem Renaissance, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - Harper Hospital Boycott, 1998 (Box 36)
  - Freeman Hendrix, 2004-2005 (Box 36)
  - City of Highland Park, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Community College, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Historic Districts Association, undated (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Lions Club, undated (Box 36)
  - Highland Park McDonalds, undated (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Omni Bank, undated (Box 36)
  - Highland Park Pubic Schools, 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Hill and Flowers Public Relations, Inc., 1996 (Box 36)
  - Historic Sites, undated (Box 36)
  - Historical Highland Park, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - Historically Black Colleges, scattered dates (Box 36)
  - House of David -- Cold Storage Building, 1992-1995 (Box 36)
  - Inmates, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Jazz, 1995 (Box 36)
  - Jean Klock Park, 2000s (Box 36)
  - Bert Johnson, 2006 (Box 36)
  - Journalists, undated (Box 36)
  - Julie Weiss vs. Harbor Shores Community Redevelopment, Inc., 2009 (Box 36)
  - Juneteenth, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Juvenile Exporting, 1995 (Box 36)
  - Keep Detroit Beautiful, 2001 (Box 36)
  - Charles Kelly, 1981-1982 (Box 36)
  - Super K-Mart, 1996 (Box 36)
  - Lansing, Michigan, undated (Box 37)
  - Lewis College of Business, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Liberty Focus School, undated (Box 37)
  - Libya, undated (Box 37)
  - The Links, Inc. (Detroit Metro chapters), 1996 (Box 37)
  - Little Rock Nine, undated (Box 37)
  - Malcolm X Academy, undated (Box 37)
  - Mandatory Minimums -- Ed Vaughn Bill, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Martin Luther King High School, undated (Box 37)
  - Medal of Honor Recipient, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Media, undated (Box 37)
  - Metro Detroit Chapter of Links, 1996-1997 (Box 37)
  - Michigan ACORN, undated (Box 37)
  - Michigan Association for Leadership Development, Inc., 1996 (Box 37)
  - Michigan Citizen Information, undated (Box 37)
  - Michigan Week, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Miller Brewing Co., undated (Box 37)
  - Military, undated (Box 37)
  - Million Man Fraternity, Inc., undated (Box 37)
  - Million Man March, October 16, 1995 (Box 37)
  - Million Women, March, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 37)
  - Mission Apparel and Gifts, undated (Box 37)
  - Model T. Plaza, 1996 (Box 37)
  - Models, undated (Box 37)
  - Motor City Casino, 2005 (Box 37)
  - Motown, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - Music -- Caribbean, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - Music -- Classical, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - Music -- Gospel, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - Music -- Hip Hop, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - Music -- Mecca Entertainment, 1997 (Box 37)
  - Music -- Rap, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - NAACP, scattered dates (Box 37)
  - NAACP -- Detroit Chapter, 1990s (Box 38)
  - NASA, undated (Box 38)
  - Nation of Islam, undated (Box 38)
  - National African American Leadership Summit, 1996 (Box 38)
  - National Association of Market Developers, Inc., undated (Box 38)
  - National Association of Negro Business and Professional Women's Club, Inc., 1997 (Box 38)
  - National Basketball Association (NBA), 1996 (Box 38)
  - National Black Chamber of Commerce, undated (Box 38)
  - National Black United Front, 1996 (Box 38)
  - National Black Women's Political Leadership Caucus, undated (Box 38)
  - National Conference of Black Mayors, Inc., 1997 (Box 38)
  - National Council of Negro Women (NCNW), 1996 (Box 38)
  - National Minority Supplier Development Council (NMSDC), undated (Box 38)
  - National Newspaper Publishers Association (NNPA), 1996 (Box 38)
  - National Political Congress of Black Women, 1996-1997 (Box 38)
  - National Urban League, 1996 (Box 38)
  - Native Americans, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Nature's Option, undated (Box 38)
  - N'Corba, 1997 (Box 38)
  - Negro Baseball, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - New Detroit, Inc., 1996 (Box 38)
  - New Marcus Garvey Movement, 1998 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper Articles, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Newspaper Strike, 1995-1997 (Box 38)
  - Nigeria, 1997 (Box 38)
  - Michigan Citizen -- Night at the Fisher, undated (Box 38)
  - Nordstrom, undated (Box 38)
  - Nsoroma Institute, 1996 (Box 38)
  - Oakland University, undated (Box 38)
  - Oklahoma City Bombing, April 19, 1995 (Box 38)
  - Olympic Games, 1990s (Box 38)
  - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc., undated (Box 38)
  - Omni Bank, 1998 (Box 38)
  - One Stop Capital Stop (OSCS), 1996 (Box 38)
  - Operation Push, 1995 (Box 38)
  - Organ Donor Foundation, undated (Box 38)
  - Pan Africanism, 1989 (Box 38)
  - Perry Marketing Group, Inc., undated (Box 38)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, undated (Box 38)
  - Political Protests, 1968 (Box 38)
  - Politicians, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Prayer Works Production, Inc., undated (Box 38)
  - Precious Memories Wedding Chapel, undated (Box 38)
  - Prisons, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Privatization, 2001 (Box 38)
  - Proposal 209, 1996 (Box 38)
  - Protocols of the Progressive Urban United Front (PUUF), 2000 (Box 38)
  - Pulte, 1998 (Box 38)
  - Push, undated (Box 38)
  - Racism, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Reach Small Business Development Center, undated (Box 38)
  - Rebellion, 1967 (Box 38)
  - Reggie McKenzie Foundation, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Renaissance High School Varsity Chorus, undated (Box 38)
  - Renaissance Zones, 1996-1997 (Box 38)
  - Black Republicans, 1996 (Box 38)
  - Residency Requirements -- McPhail Resolution, October 2005 (Box 38)
  - Riverfront Casinos, 2000-2001 (Box 38)
  - John Salley Mansion, 1995 (Box 38)
  - Save Detroit -- Recall Mayor Archer, 1999 (Box 38)
  - Scheff and Washington, 1997 (Box 38)
  - School Board Interviews, 1995-1996 (Box 38)
  - Schools, 2001 (Box 38)
  - Second Baptist Church of Detroit, 1991 (Box 38)
  - Shell Oil, 1997 (Box 38)
  - Shrine of the Black Madonna, undated (Box 38)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho, undated (Box 38)
  - Slavery, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Smart Transportation, undated (Box 38)
  - Save Our Sons and Daughters (SOSAD), undated (Box 38)
  - South Africa, 1996 (Box 38)
  - South Carolina State Legislature, scattered dates (Box 38)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, scattered dates (Box 39)
  - State Takeover Schools, 1997 (Box 39)
  - Storm, July 2, 1997 (Box 39)
  - Television Programs, scattered dates (Box 39)
  - Tennis, undated (Box 39)
  - Texaco, 1996 (Box 39)
  - Theatre, undated (Box 39)
  - Top Ladies of Distinction, Inc., undated (Box 39)
  - Track and Field, scattered dates (Box 39)
  - Trans Africa, undated (Box 39)
  - Tuskegee Experience, 1997 (Box 39)
  - TV Journalists, scattered dates (Box 39)
  - UNICEF, 1997 (Box 39)
  - United Negro College Fund (UNCF), 1996-1997 (Box 39)
  - University of Michigan, 1996-1997 (Box 39)
  - Universoul Circus, 1997-1998 (Box 39)
  - Uniworld, Inc., undated (Box 39)
  - UPSET, undated (Box 39)
  - Voting Rights, 1996 (Box 39)
  - Wayne County, scattered dates (Box 39)
  - Wayne County Commission, 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - Wayne County Community College, undated (Box 39)
  - Wayne State University, 1996-1997 (Box 39)
  - Wayne State University School of Medicine, 2000-2001 (Box 39)
  - West Africa, 1990s (Box 39)
  - WGPR, undated (Box 39)
  - Wolverine Bar Association, undated (Box 39)
  - Women and Ergonomics, 2001 (Box 39)
  - Workers World Party, 1996 (Box 39)
  - Youth, undated (Box 39)
  - Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, undated (Box 39)
- Reporter's Notes, 1967-2015
  The Reporter's Notes series (4 linear feet, 1967-2015 and undated) consists of the research files and documentation that were used to produce news stories for the Michigan Citizen throughout its publication. Materials in this series are arranged alphabetically and were gathered and created by the various reporters that worked for the Michigan Citizen.
  - ACLU -- Debtors Prison, 2011 (Box 40)
  - ACORN/Voter Suppression, November 2008 (Box 40)
  - Actionline -- Combined Annual Report, 1997 (Box 40)
  - African American Chamber of Commerce, 1998 (Box 40)
  - ALCOS Professional Liability, 2006 (Box 40)
  - Ambassador Bridge, 2009 (Box 40)
  - American Legion Boys State Program, 2013 (Box 40)
  - Amerisure Insurance, 2008 (Box 40)
  - Anthony Austin Case File, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Auto Insurance Legislation, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Bank of Birmingham, 2007 (Box 40)
  - Bank of Bloomfield, 2007 (Box 40)
  - Bankruptcy, 2014 (Box 40)
  - Benton Harbor -- Clippings, scattered dates (Box 40)
  - Benton Harbor -- Edgewater Redevelopment, 1998 (Box 40)
  - Benton Harbor -- Financial Info, scattered dates (Box 40)
  - Benton Harbor -- Grievance Files, 1980s (Box 40)
  - Benton Harbor Property, scattered dates (Box 40)
  - Blighted Area Rehabilitation, 1996 (Box 40)
  - Brainwashed and Ignored by Snow F. Grigsby, 1976 (Box 40)
  - Cable Deregulation -- Michigan, 2007 (Box 40)
  - Census -- Prisoner Diaspora, 2010 (Box 40)
  - Centers for Disease Control Information, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Centurion Ministries, Inc., 1995 (Box 40)
  - Chokwe Lumumba, 2014 (Box 40)
  - Citizens Insurance-Business owner's Coverage Form, 2001 (Box 40)
  - City Council Marshall Plan Proposal, 2008 (Box 40)
  - City of Benton Harbor, 1990s (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit, 2009-2011 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit, 2011-2012 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit, 2013-2014 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Board of Education, 2011 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Charter Revision Commission, 2011 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Complaint Files, 2012 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Finance Department, 2007-2011 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Financial Information, 2013 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Future Solid Waste Plan, 2007 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Legislative Structure, 2007-2011 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Lighting Authority and Electricity, 2012 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Policy on Food Security, 2008 (Box 40)
  - City of Detroit -- Reform Program, 2012 (Box 40)
  - City Media Advertising Contracts/FOIA, 2013 (Box 40)
  - Coalition Union Contract Savings and Revenue Generation, undated (Box 40)
  - Cobo Hall Authority, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Corporate Council, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Consent Agreement between the City of Inkster and the City of Inkster Financial Review Team, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Clean Water -- Green Jobs, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Cockrel Aide -- Lawsuit Settlement, 2006 (Box 40)
  - Communication between City Council and GDRRA, 2007-2008 (Box 40)
  - Considine -- Detroit Recreation Centers, 2005-2006 (Box 40)
  - Crittendon Files -- Call outs to be done, 2012 (Box 40)
  - CVS Caremark, undated (Box 40)
  - Dale Rich -- Black History, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Data Driven Detroit, 2010 (Box 40)
  - David Lee Walton -- Prisoner File, scattered dates (Box 40)
  - Davis Aerospace Technical High School, undated (Box 40)
  - Democracy for Sale: Subverting Voting Rights, Collective Bargaining, and Accountability under Michigan's Emergency Manager Law, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Detroit Black Chamber of Commerce, 2012 (Box 40)
  - Detroit Board of Education, 2009-2011 (Box 40)
  - Detroit Board of Education -- Rochelle Riley, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Detroit Branch NAACP vs. Rick Snyder, Andrew Dillon, and Ruth Johnson, 2013 (Box 40)
  - Detroit City Charter -- Ethics and Provision, undated (Box 40)
  - Detroit City Council, 2009 (Box 40)
  - Detroit City Council, 2013 (Box 40)
  - Detroit -- City Council, Fiscal Analysis Division, 2010-2011 (Box 40)
  - Detroit Council by District, scattered dates (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Debunking the Myth of Mayoral Control, 2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Emergency Manager Legislation, 2011-2012 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Environmentalism, 2000s (Box 41)
  - Detroit Financial Advisory Board, 2012 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Financial Stability Agreement, 2012 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Legal Case Files, 2008-2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit -- Memorial for Dr. Asa Grant Hilliard, III, 2008 (Box 41)
  - Detroit People's Movement Assembly, 2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Police -- Memo on Kilpatrick, 2003 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Library, 2008-2013 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools, 2010 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools -- Board, 2013 (Box 41)
  - Detroit Public Schools Bond/Real Estate Transactions, 2008-2010 (Box 41)